https://balanceanddizziness.org/about/policies/privacy-policy/

Skip to primary navigation Skip to main content
NAVIGATIONBalance SystemSymptomsDisorders CloseVestibular Disorders CloseAcoustic NeuromaAge-related Dizziness and ImbalanceAutoimmune Inner Ear Disease (AIED)Benign Paroxysmal Positional Vertigo (BPPV)Bilateral VestibulopathyCANVAS SyndromeCervicogenic DizzinessCholesteatomaConcussionEnlarged Vestibular AqueductLabyrinthine InfarctionLabyrinthitisMal de Débarquement Syndrome (MdDS)Ménière’s DiseaseMotion and Cyber SicknessOtosclerosisPediatric Vestibular DisordersPerilymph FistulaPersistent Postural-Perceptual Dizziness (PPPD)Ramsay Hunt SyndromeSecondary Endolymphatic HydropsSemicircular Canal DehiscenceVestibular MigraineVestibular NeuritisVestibular ParoxysmiaVestibular ToxicityVisually Induced Dizziness CloseMultifactorial CausesOther CausesImbalance without DizzinessStatistics CloseDiagnosis & Treatment ClosePatient JourneyPreparation for AppointmentsPrimary Care PhysiciansOther Health ProfessionalsDiagnostic TestsDiagnostic Services (BC)Vestibular RehabilitationVestibular Rehab Video $10Cognitive Behavioural TherapyMedicationTreatment DevicesSurgical TreatmentsAlternative TreatmentsFuture Treatments CloseHelp Yourself CloseBuild Your Wellness ToolkitKeep a Health DiaryTime ManagementRelaxation TechniquesPhysical ActivityVestibular Rehab Video $10Deal with DepressionEat WellSleep HabitsVision ChallengesPrevent FallsOvercome Fear of FallingAt Home, Work & SchoolOut & AboutEmergency PlansMove From Survive to Thrive CloseBe Inspired CloseOur StoriesTales from Our BlogShare Your StoryInspiring BooksFamous Dizzy People CloseGet Support CloseAsk UsAsk an Expert Q&As CloseSubmit Your Question CloseVestibular Rehab Video $10Who Can Treat YouWhere to Get TestedPractitioners ListFor Family and FriendsCommunity ServicesLegal ServicesEventsPatient Handouts Close
Search
Search
You are here: Home / About / Policies / Privacy Policy
PRIVACY POLICY
LAST UPDATE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY – June 1, 2018
BEFORE USING OUR SITE, PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY.
This Privacy Policy is applicable to BC Balance and Dizziness Disorders Society ("Organisation") and sets out our policy on the gathering and use of information on this website ("Site"). The Organisation is committed to providing safe websites for visitors of all ages and has implemented this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. The Organisation complies with Canadian Federal and Provincial privacy laws and regulations including the Personal Information and Electronic Documents Act. Our website URL is https://balanceanddizziness.org.
There may be links from our Site to other websites; note that this Privacy Policy applies only to our Site and not to websites of other companies or organizations to which our Site may be linked. You must check on any linked sites for the privacy policy that applies to that site and/or make any necessary inquiries in respect of that privacy policy with the operator of the linked site. These links to third party websites are provided as a convenience and are for informational purposes only. The Organisation does not endorse, and is not responsible for, these linked websites.
Although you are not required to register to access our Site, you may be asked to provide us with personal information when you visit certain sections of our Site. Your use of our Site signifies your acknowledgement and consent to our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not continue to use our Site. Your continued use of the Sites signifies your acceptance of these terms and any changes in effect at the time of use.
COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
Personal Information is information about you that identifies you as an individual, for example, your name, address, email address, or telephone number.
We collect information that you voluntarily provide to us through emails, responses to surveys, search functions, questionnaires, feedback, membership forms, donation forms, Ask an Expert forms and the like. We may also ask you to provide additional information such as your email address, mailing address or phone number if you want to obtain additional services, information, participate in a survey or to resolve complaints or concerns.
During the membership and donation purchase process, donor and member data is collected by a data management application called Sumac. This data is stored in a database in Montreal, QC, is only accessible by this Organisation and is not shared with any other institution. Here is a link to Sumac's Privacy Policy.
Additionally, donation data is also collected by CanadaHelps.org when their donation form is used on this Site. The CanadaHelp’s form is secure and complies with the highest level of Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards (PCI DSS).
We use SiteGround as our hooting company. Here is a link to SiteGround's Data Processing Agreement which covers data stored on their servers, such as Web mail, backups, etc.
HOW DOES THE ORGANISATION USE INFORMATION GATHERED ABOUT ONLINE VISITORS?
Before forwarding us any personal information, please be advised that any information gathered on our Site may be used in the aggregate for research and development relating to our Site and/or for future site development and to send you promotional materials. In particular, we may use general information gathered about visitors to our Site for the following purposes: to monitor interest in our organisation and to assist us in tailoring the content of our Site to visitors' needs by collecting information about visitors' preferences through the tracking of page view patterns on our Site; and, in circumstances where you have indicated that you wish to receive additional information, to send you information about us and promotional material together with details of any campaigns or drives for donations or memberships that we may run from time to time.
PROMOTIONAL AND INFORMATIONAL OFFERS
With the permission of an online visitor, information submitted at the time of registration or submission may be used for marketing and promotional purposes by the Organisation provided notice of this fact is made available online. If a visitor objects to such use for any reason, he/she may prevent that use, either by email request or by modifying the registration information provided. The Organisation uses reasonable efforts to maintain visitors' information in a secure environment. If you have submitted personal information and want to change it or opt-out, please contact us as described below.
DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION
The Organisation will not disclose personal information that you provide on its Site to any third parties other than to an Organisation agent except: i) in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy, or ii) to comply with legal requirements such as a law, regulation, warrant, subpoena or court order, and/or iii) if you are reporting an adverse event/side effect, in which case the Organisation may be required to disclose such information to bodies such as, but not limited to, Canadian and/or international regulatory authorities. Please note that any of these disclosures may involve the storage or processing of personal information outside of Canada and may therefore be subject to different privacy laws than those applicable in Canada, including laws that require the disclosure of personal information to governmental authorities under circumstances that are different than those that apply in Canada.
COOKIES
The Organisation, in common with many web site operators, may use standard technology called "cookies" on its site. Cookies are small data files that are downloaded onto your computer when you visit a particular website. You can disable cookies by turning them off in your browser; however, some areas of the Site may not function properly if you do so.
If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.
If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.
When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select "Remember Me," your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.
ANALYTICS
We use Google Analytics and the Monster Insights plugin with the EU compliance add-on to obtain anonymous analytics data. Google Analytics' Terms of Service include a privacy section.
PROTECTION OF CHILDREN ONLINE
The Organisation considers the protection of children's privacy, especially online, to be of the utmost importance. We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from children nor do we allow them to become registered users of, or to request information through, our Site or help-seeking information line.
ADDITIONAL TERMS
The following additional information applies to registration on our Site. Generally, you are not required to provide personal information as a condition of using our Site, except as may be necessary to provide you with a product or service that you have requested. However, some parts of our Site may be restricted to certain individuals such as health care professionals or our members and we may require these individuals to register upon entry by providing us with certain information, such as a username and password.
PROTECTION OF INFORMATION:
Our Commitment to Security
We have put in place physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security, and correctly use the information we collect online. The Organisation applies security safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of the information, such as retaining information in secure facilities and making personal information accessible only to authorized employees, volunteers or Board members on a need-to-know basis.
Our website is encrypted using SSL (secure socket layer).
As payment gateways we use PayPal, Bambora and CanadaHelps. None of these payment gateways share your personal financial details with us.
Storage of Information:
Personal information that you share with us on our Site is stored on secured database servers at third-party data centres (in whatever country they may be located).
POLICY CHANGE:
If we alter our Privacy Policy, any changes will be posted on this page of our Site so that you are always informed of the information we collect about you, how we use it and the circumstances under which we may disclose it.
ACCEPTANCE OF OUR PRIVACY POLICY:
By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of our Privacy Policy, and you adhere to the terms and conditions posted on the Site. By submitting your information, you agree that it will be governed by our Privacy Policy.
To be removed from our database or to direct questions or concerns about your data to us, please email info@bcbalanceanddizzines.org.
If you find our information valuable, we ask you for your help. The cause of supporting those affected by balance and dizziness disorders with up-to-date, evidence-based information written for Canadians, needs you. Will you consider becoming its champion by making a gift or becoming a member?
MenuHomeBlogShare Your StoryAboutContactPractitioners ListWho Can Treat YouWellness ToolkitEventsJoin or RenewDonateBuy Rehab Video (MP4) – only $10Site Map
Contact Information
BC Balance and Dizziness
325-5525 West Boulevard
Vancouver, BC V6M 3W6
Voice Mail
Lower Mainland: 604-878-8383
Toll Free: 1-866-780-2233 (Canada only)
Email: info@balanceanddizziness.org
Upcoming Events
Please check Upcoming Events for details.
Please Donate Today
Practitioners List
Become a Professional Member
Translate »Scroll Up
